<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Developing Notes - Tag - p1nant0m</title>
        <link>https://p1nant0m.xyz/en/tags/developing-notes/</link>
        <description>Developing Notes - Tag - p1nant0m</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>wgblike@gmail.com (p1nant0m)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>wgblike@gmail.com (p1nant0m)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 09:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://p1nant0m.xyz/en/tags/developing-notes/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>6.824-RaftLab-Part2D-Development Quicknotes</title>
    <link>https://p1nant0m.xyz/en/2022-03-18-raft-part2d/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 09:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>p1nant0m</author>
    <guid>https://p1nant0m.xyz/en/2022-03-18-raft-part2d/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Overview  This topic can be found under Lab2 instruction.
 Modifying Raft to cooperate with services that persistently store a &ldquo;snapshot&rdquo; of their state from time to time, at which point Raft discards log entries that precede the snapshot.
It&rsquo;s now possible for a follower to fall so far behind that the leader has discarded the log entries it needs to catch up; the leader must then send a snapshot plus the log starting at the time of the snapshot.
diagram of Raft interactions
KeyValue-Store Server Architecture" KeyValue-Store Server Architecture  Raft must provide the following function that the service can call with a serialized snapshot of its state. In this way, Raft can discard the log entries safely preceding this Snapshot()
Snapshot(index int, snapshot []byte)
The index argument indicates the highest log entry that&rsquo;s reflected in the snapshot. Raft should discard its log entries before that point. You&rsquo;ll need to revise your Raft code to operate while storing only the tail of the log.
You&rsquo;ll need to implement the InstallSnapshot RPC discussed in the paper that allows a Raft leader to tell a lagging Raft peer to replace its state with a snapshot. You will likely need to think through how InstallSnapshot should interact with the state and rules in Figure 2.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
